welcome back
today we are going to start working on the LuV quests
and
the first thing we want to do
is to finish working on our naquadah setup
that requires a precision assembler
so we craft a new one
since the last one had been repurposed
but since we lack Redstone
we shall make a new ore drilling rig first
and to keep track of its progress from our base
we can use this new cover
we now have 3 miners
and they are all out of drilling fluid
maybe we have throttled the flow too much last time
and after increasing the flow
they are all working
and after not much time
we are ready to craft our new assembler
and we also are reminded on
why we were feeding so little drilling fluid to the miners
our ore processing plant is not being fed enough power
since we have no hurry
we lower back the drilling fluid speed
just kidding
we upgrade our mineral processing plant
the other thing we need
is some precise casings for our new assembler
but those require a material
which has to be cooked at ZPM voltage
which as usual
we will do by using two energy hatches of the previous tier
however
while this allow us to make the required material
it is also going to use half of our current power production
and our battery is quite empty already
so we quickly add some more reactors to our vacuum setup
which fixed the issue
until more machines turned on
thus we also upgraded our fluid plant
starting from upgrading our heat exchanger
into a Whakawhiti Wera XL
and with an extra large heat exchanger
we also want to extra large turbine
with all that power
we can now run our volcanoes with two LuV energy hatches
and to keep up with those
we also got a mega vacuum freezer
that thing will cool 250 items at a time
but it also eat that much more energy
thus causing huge power spikes
that our battery can't alleviate easily
and the main issue is that it has no capacity
to craft better capacitor elements
we need naquadah alloy
and to be cooked
we need even more naquadah enough for the coils of a whole EBF
so it is finally time to complete the precision assembler
with precise casings that we planned a long time ago
and with that
we can now craft the neutron activator
required to complete our naquadah processing plant
that machine does not require power
but it must be kept at a specific neutron kinetic energy in order to work properly
if we turn it on when outside of the recipe range
the ingredients will be turned into useless waste
to regulate the kinetic energy
we can use neutron detectors
neutron accelerators
and machine controller covers
based on how high we build our neutron activator
and how powerful the neutron accelerator
it will take more or less time to reach the target kinetic energy
once we get there
we can start processing the naquadah
and we must make sure the kinetic energy is kept in check by the covers
if it goes too high the structure will explode
but what we are actually getting is naquadahine
that stuff can be easily converted into ingots or dusts
but we want to keep it like that
because in that form
it makes wafers 10 times faster
so we quickly make patterns for the three main naquadah forms
and craft on demand the required version
and with all that naquadah
we can upgrade our EBF
so that we can craft some better batteries
and by swapping just two capacitors
we have three times the capacity
and now that our power issues are fixed
we can move on to the next task
crafting a fusion reactor
and just when we started working on the controller
we faced our first issue
we lack indium
to get it
we have only two ways that aren't too convoluted
one is destroying more aluminum in the setup we already have
the other one is use the byproduct of naquadria processing
since we have some of that stuff lying around
we can work that to get some extra indium
and that is one energy intensive job
but it already gave us enough indium
for the reactor control computer
the next expensive thing we need
is some superconducting coils
which are going to require more indium
thus we shall have more ore mining rigs across multiple dimensions
to mine minerals that contain traces of indium
and of course
to keep up with all of those minerals
we also want to upgrade our ore working facility
which is now becoming a huge source of pollution
the last component for our fusion reactor
is LuV machine casings
those are made entirely out of rhodium plated palladium
which has to be cooked inside an EBF using some noble gas
but we run out of those gases
the easiest one to make is are gone out of liquid air
however out current setup is too slow
so we shall swap our two small vacuum freezers with a big one
that will work 250 times faster
and after some time
we have finally completed our fusion reactor
before we can use it
we have to wait for its 16 energy hatches to slowly load up its internal energetic buffer
each recipe requires a specific amount of energy to be started
we are going to use this first reactor
to constantly produce helium plasma
that stuff has a high energy density
but requires a plasma generator
to make it
we need deuterium and either tritium or helium 3
since helium 3 can be pumped from many planets
we chose that option
and we will want to use the highest tier of oil drilling rig
which however need at least IV power
and since our fuel is slowly depleting
we shall power that one with the plasma
but since we need its output for the plasma
we shall kick start the loop by using some tritium
to get it
we manually centrifuge some deuterium from our new deuterium setup
we are not making this a definitive way of making plasma
due to the awful production ratio of 16 hydrogen to 1 tritium
it indeed took quite some time for this tritium to be ready
and now we can hit our fusion reactor with a hammer
to turn it on
since there are no other power switches
once the first plasma batch is done
we also manually fuse some europium
we need it to craft the plasma generator
now we can go to Mercury
where we can easily locate some cheap helium 3
with our portable scanner
we build the oil drilling rig structure
and set up a transceiver to swap fluids with the fusion reactor
and once everything is ready
we can turn it on
and realize that
once again we have forgotten something to finish our building
this time
instead of flying all the way back to our base
take the missing pipes and come back
we use a specter key to open a portal to a pocket of space
where we have access to ae2
while that does not look much different
consider that it takes about one minute to do the same task with a rocket
and now the pumping can begin
and with our new reliable source of portable fuel
we can start expanding our drilling capabilities
meanwhile our ore processing plant is expanding its pollution cloud
which is starting to make our green grass fall as sand
so we shall try to at least improve some mufflers
however
while those upgrades allowed us to gather the materials
required for a second fusion reactor
we are also running out of power again
to increase our production
we could burn some of the plasma that we are already producing
however right now
we have no access to generators that can convert the energy at a high enough rate
even the multi block turbine is limited by its dynamo hatch
and the best we can craft only allows for 100 thousand EU per tick
but I think that
we could also look into some more imaginative power source
such as naquadah
that stuff comes in different forms
and can also be used in many ways
and I think the easiest way to extract its energy
is to shove it inside some tungsten cells
and then shove those inside our old vacuum cooled nuclear reactor
it can be clustered in many ways
but I think we shall go with the one with the highest energy density
however
that thing is going to be quite complex to manage and quite interesting
so I think it shall have its own dedicated episode
where we will be trying some crazy stuff
you can wait for the finished result
or you come see the live streams
to see the humiliating fails
bye bye
欢迎回来！
今天我们开始进行 LuV 的任务
并且
我们要做的第一件事
是完成硅岩处理
这需要精密组装机
所以我们先做个新的
因为上一个已经另有他用
但因为我们缺少红石
所以先来个采矿厂
为了可以在基地监控它的进程
我们可以用这个新覆盖板
我们现在有三个矿厂
而且他们的钻井液都用完了
也许我们上次节流控制过甚
增加流量后
他们都运行良好
过不了多久
我们已准备好制作新精密组装机
我们也发现了
为什么给矿机这么少的钻井液
我们的矿处系统供电不足
反正我们也不着急
将钻井液的流量调低回去吧
开玩笑啦
我们升级了矿处系统
我们要做的另一件事
是为新组装机准备精密外壳
但它所需要的材料
必须在 ZPM 电压下制作
像往常一样
我们使用 LuV 能源仓升压
然而
虽然这样能烧炼所需的材料
但它将吃掉我们一半的电力产能
而我们的电容库已经空了
所以我们快速添加更多的强冷核电
这解决了燃眉之急
但更多机器启动就无能为力
因此，我们也升级了流体反应堆
从升级热交换器开始
把它升级成超大热交换机
由于有了超大热交换机
升级涡轮也势在必行
有了这么充裕的电力
用两个 LuV 能源仓运行炽焰高炉不在话下
为了跟上高炉的效率
我们还做了个巨型真空冷冻机
它能一次性冷却 250 个物品
但它也会消耗更多的能量
从而导致我们的电容库
有些无法应对功率的巨大波动
最主要问题是它容量太小
制作更好的电容
我们需要硅岩合金
而且想要获得它
我们需要更多的硅岩来做高炉线圈
所以是时候完成精密组装机了
用我们早就计划好的精密外壳
有了这个
我们现在可以制造中子活化器了
作为硅岩加工中的必需品
这台机器不需要电力
但它必须保持在特定的中子动能才能正常工作
如果我们在配方所需范围之外打开它
材料会变成废料
想自动调节中子动能
我们可以用中子传感器
中子加速器
以及机器控制覆盖板
根据中子活化器的高度
以及中子加速器的威力
决定机器达到目标动能的时间
一旦我们到了目标动能
就可以开始处理硅岩了
我们必须确保覆盖板可以控制动能水平
如果动能太高，结构就会爆炸
但我们实际上得到的是氧化硅岩粉
那东西很容易变成锭或粉
但我们想保持这样
因为在那种形式下
制作晶圆的速度可以翻 10 倍
所以我们快速为三种主要的硅岩形态制作样板
并按任务所需制作它们
有了这些硅岩
我们可以升级高炉
升级到更好的电容
通过升级两个电容
我们就有了三倍的容量
现在我们的电力问题解决了
我们可以继续下一个任务
制作聚变反应堆
正当我们要制作控制器时
我们遇到了第一个问题
我们缺少铟
想得到它
我们只有两种不太复杂的方法
一是继续土法制铟
另一个是使用超能硅岩的副产品
正好我们有一些超能硅岩
我们用它来获得一些额外的铟
这是一项高耗能工作
但它已经给了我们足够的铟
来制作反应堆控制器
下一个造价不菲的东西
是一些超导线圈
这将需要更多的铟
因此，我们做了更多跨维度的采矿厂
开采含有微量铟的矿物
当然还有
为了能跟上采矿速度
我们升级了矿处设备
而它正成为一个巨大的污染源
聚变反应堆的最后一个部件
是 LuV 机器外壳
它们是由镀铑钯制成的
通过在高炉中使用惰性气体制作
但是我们的稀有气体用完了
最简单的方法是使用液态空气
但是我们现在的产能太低
所以我们将两个小冰箱换成一个大冰箱
这是 250 倍的效率提升
一段时间后
我们终于完成了聚变反应堆
在可以使用它之前
我们必须等待 16 个能源仓慢慢缓存能量
每个配方都有特定的启动能量阈值
我们将使用第一个反应堆
不断产生氦等离子体
那东西能量密度很高
但需要等离子发电机
要制作氦等离子体
我们需要氘和氚或氦-3
因为氦-3可以从很多星球上抽取
就是它了
我们要用最高级的油气钻井
然而，它至少需要 IV 级电源
由于我们的化石燃料正在慢慢耗尽
我们将用等离子为钻机供电
但既然造等离子体需要它的输出物
我们先用氚来启动循环
为了得到它
我们从新的氘产线中手动离心一些氘
我们没有把它作为制造等离子的最终方法
因为 16: 1 的恐怖产率实在难以承受
氚元素确实花了不少时间才准备好
现在我们可以用软锤
来启动聚变反应堆了
只因他没有启动按钮
一旦第一批等离子体完成
我们还手工聚变出一些铯
我们需要它来制造等离子发电机
现在我们可以去水星了
使用便携探矿仪
我们可以很轻松地找到氦-3
我们放下油气钻井
并配置空间传送器与核聚变反应堆交换流体
一旦一切准备就绪
我们将其启动
又意识到一个问题
我们忘带采矿管道了
这一次
我们不直接飞回基地
去拿我们遗落的管道
我们用灵魂之匙打开空间传送门
来访问 AE 网络
虽然这看起来没什么不同
但想想用火箭做同样的任务大约需要一分钟
现在可以开始抽氦-3了
有了新的可靠的便携式燃料来源
我们可以开始增强我们的钻井效能
与此同时，我们的矿处的污染有些难以遏制
它开始让青草沙化
所以我们至少要改进一些消声仓
然而
虽然这些升级可以让我们
收集到第二个聚变反应堆所需的材料
但我们电力又耗尽了
为了增加发电量
我们可以烧一些已经产生的等离子
然而现在
我们做不了具有足够高能量转换速度的发电机
即使是多方块涡轮也受到其动力仓的限制
我们能做的最好的动力仓只有 100 kEU/t
但我认为
我们还可以使用一些更有想象力的能源
比如硅岩发电
那东西有不同的形式
能以各种方式使用
我认为提取它能量的最简单方法
是把它塞进钨单元里
然后把它们塞进我们老式的强冷核电
它可以以多种方式排布
但我认为我们应该选择能量密度最高的那个
然而
那东西管理起来会很复杂，也很有趣。
所以我认为它应该有自己专属的一集
我们将尝试一些疯狂的东西
你可以等待完成后的结果
或者来看看我的直播
看到一些耻辱的败北
拜拜
（数据发射器覆盖板）
（我自己玩的时候一直没搞懂为什么是这机器名）
（之后用巨冰箱/大冰箱指代它）
（准确来说是256）